beadingdaily.com 2008-09-11

# Beading Daily

**Your Guarantee of SPAM-Free Privacy**  
We at Aspire Media/Interweave Press, LLC (referred to hereunder as IWP, we, us, our, etc.), producer of knittingdaily.com and affiliated web sites (the Sites), believe that you have the right to know how your personal and other information may be used or disclosed. You take your privacy seriously, and we respect your concerns. Accordingly, we have created this Privacy Statement in order to educate you as to how we collect information, what we do with it, and what controls and options you have. Please read this Privacy Statement carefully, and if you have any questions or concerns, please send us a comment at privacy@interweave.com

Unless otherwise indicated, this Privacy Statement applies only to information collected via the Site(s), and not to any off-line or non-Site related activities of IWP or its affiliates. 

**Gathering and Use of Information**  
We and our third party vendors and service providers collect data from you (Information) in different ways and via many different parts of our Site(s): when you (1) register to become a Site(s) member or use particular features of the Site(s), (2) enter one of our contests or sweepstakes, (3) use one of our many patterns/projects, (4) send us a question, or (5) buy one of our products. Even if you are just surfing the Site(s) and reading a how-to article, we may collect information from you, such as your IP address and the particular web pages that you visit on our Site(s). 

**Information Pertaining to Children and Minor** s  
IWP does not want to collect Information from minors (children under 13 years of age, or any other age defined under applicable law). If we become aware that a minor is attempting to or has submitted Information via this Site(s), we will notify the user that we may not accept his or her Information. We will then expunge any personally identifiable information from our records. 

**Registration Information  
**Registration is required to access certain areas of this Site(s). In order to register, you must provide us with information as prompted, which may include your name, age group, gender, zip code, email address, interests, occupation, how you found out about our Site(s) and other information (Registration Information).

We use your Registration Information to maintain your Site(s) account. We may use your Registration Information to contact you if there is a problem with your account or other related purposes, to facilitate, complete, or confirm a transaction that you have entered into on or through the Site(s), or if we substantially change our services, the Site(s) (or your standing or status with respect to our Site(s) or services), or the Site(s) policies and feel that we need to update all of our registered users.

We may also analyze Registration Information to understand who visits our Site(s), so that we can better design the Site(s) to serve you more effectively. In the event we engage a third party to perform this analysis for us, we will have agreements with the third party requiring it to abide by privacy protections similar to those contained in this Privacy Statement. In addition, we may share the results of our analysis with advertisers in order to feature the products that will best serve your needs, but we will not share any of your personally identifiable Registration Information without your prior consent, except as otherwise indicated in this Privacy Statement. For purposes of this Privacy Statement, whenever we use the term “personally identifiable” we mean information that can be used to reasonably identify you, including by way of example, your name, phone number, email address, and postal address. 

**Contests and Sweepstakes  
**We may from time to time offer contests and sweepstakes. To enter a sweepstake or contest, you may be asked to provide your name, mailing address, email address, and your phone number and other information. Depending on the nature of the contest or sweepstake, we may also request additional information, such as your preferences, tastes, opinions, interests, and behavior. We use your contact Information to notify winners. Otherwise, we do not share personally identifiable sweepstake or contest-related Information with third parties, except as otherwise indicated in this Privacy Statement. 

**Projects/Patterns**  
Our Site(s) offer projects/patterns that prompt you for information and we ask for your email address in conjunction with such projects/patterns. We use the Information you provide regarding your projects/patterns to perform complex automated tasks like suggesting other recommended related products. We do not share this Information with third parties other than our third party service providers who assist us in providing such information. We require that these third party service providers abide by privacy protections similar to those contained in this Privacy Statement. 

**Buying Merchandise  
**You can order IWP merchandise online or by email. If you do, IWP, as applicable, will collect your product order along with your billing and shipping information. This Information is used to fulfill your order and bill you for your purchase, and also to analyze our product sales so that we can better meet your needs. Our products may be shipped directly by the vendor, in which case we will share with them only the minimum required information to complete the shipping of your items. Except as otherwise indicated in this Privacy Statement, we do not share this Information with third parties. Please be aware that some products are made available by third parties on third party web sites, in which case the section below concerning third party links and web sites will apply. 

**Navigation Information/Cookies  
**When visiting our Site(s), your browser sends information to our hosting server identifying the browser you are using, your Internet Service Provider, the page you last visited, and the page you are currently visiting. IWP logs this Information and uses it to help diagnose problems with our server, to track user traffic patterns, and to generally administer the Site(s). We may also track and catalog the search terms that users enter in search forms, but this tracking is not associated with individual users, except as otherwise indicated in this Privacy Statement.

We make use of a standard feature of browser software called a “cookie” which helps us recognize you when you visit. We store your email address in a cookie file and place the file on the hard drive of your computer. This lets us identify your computer as a unique user.

Most browsers are initially set up to accept cookies. You can reset your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. If you disable cookies, however, you may find the Site(s), and many other web sites, harder to use. Cookies allow us to streamline your password entry process and customize your Site homepage, and to generally administer the Site(s). Our cookies cannot read other data off your hard-drive. 

**Access to Information  
**IWP and its employees have access to your Information. We use your Information for the purposes described above. Accordingly, IWP has established policies with respect to its employees designed to keep your Information confidential in accordance with the provisions contained in this Privacy Statement. In addition, to the extent we disclose or otherwise share your Information with third parties as described in this Privacy Statement, we require that these third parties abide by privacy protections similar to those contained in this Privacy Statement.

In addition, we engage third-party technical service providers and consultants to work on the Site(s). For example, they may host our Site, provide customer support, repair our software, or consult on security issues. We allow them access to Information, but only to the extent required by their role. In such instances, we require that these third parties abide by privacy protections similar to those contained in this Privacy Statement. 

**Information Sharing and Disclosure  
**Other than as specifically described in this Privacy Statement, we only share aggregated Information about our users. For example, we might share Information about the number of people who visit our Site(s) or their demographic information. In addition, we may share aggregated Information with market analysts, advertisers, business partners, sponsors, and any other third parties.

Except as we have noted herein, we will not share any personally identifiable Information with any third party without your express consent, unless we have a good faith belief that such action is reasonably necessary: (a) to comply with the law; (b) to comply with legal process; (c) to enforce this Privacy Statement or other Site rules and policies; (d) to respond to claims that you are engaged in activities that violate the rights of third parties; or (e) to protect the rights or interests of IWP and its service providers, provided that nothing in this paragraph shall impose a duty on IWP to make any such disclosures. 

**Transfer of Your Information  
**In the event of a merger, acquisition, consolidation, or sale of all or substantially all the assets of IWP, or in the unlikely event of a bankruptcy, we reserve the right to transfer all or part of our business, including this Site(s) and your Information, to third parties. 

**3rd Parties/Links  
**This Privacy Statement applies only to the Site(s). This Site may include links to the web sites of both our affiliated and non-affiliated entities (Other Sites), including access to content, products and services of such affiliated and non-affiliated entities. Whenever you choose to access Other Sites or non-IWP content via our Site(s), a separate browser window will launch and you will leave a certain IWP Site. We urge you to familiarize yourself with the individual privacy and other terms for each linked site prior to submitting your Information. 

**Classified Advertisements  
**This Site contains classified advertisements. These advertisements are one more way that we help you find the products and services you need. Please remember, however, that when you respond to a classified advertisement by email you are sending information to a third party and not to IWP. We cannot control the use or security of or otherwise be responsible for any information that your send to a third party, so please be careful. 

**Supplementing Your Information  
**We may supplement the Information that you provide with information we receive from third parties, for example product manufacturers or service providers. If you have any questions about the privacy policies of other companies or associations, we encourage you to contact them directly. If you believe you did not opt in or have opted-out of certain services and communications from IWP, and you continue to hear from us (except with respect to our contacting you for reasons necessary for the operation of the Site(s), which we may continue to do), please contact us immediately and we will help you update your preferences and choices in our database. 

**Blogs**  
The Site contains bulletin boards which are available to the public. Please remember that any text that you send to a bulletin board is immediately available to the general public. You should exercise caution when deciding to disclose any sensitive Information like your name, address, phone number or social security number. 

**Other Important Safety Information  
**You are responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of all passwords issued to you, and are fully responsible for all activities that occur under your passwords, whether or not expressly authorized by you. Please notify IWP immediately upon becoming aware of any actual or suspected abuse or unauthorized use of the passwords issued to you.

We urge you to use only a screen name and/or e-mail address when chatting or sending e-mail. You may wish to delete unknown e-mail attachments before opening them. They can contain destructive viruses. Remember that nothing you write on the Web is completely private - including e-mail. So be careful and think about what you type and whom you tell. Not everyone is as trustworthy and honorable as they may seem. 

**Security  
**Although we have taken reasonable security precautions, no security system is impenetrable. We cannot guarantee the security of our databases, nor can we guarantee that Information you supply will not be intercepted while being transmitted to us over the Internet. 

**Opting In; Reviewing, Correcting or Deleting Information  
**When you provide contact Information to us, you will be given the ability to “opt in” to (1) receiving communications from us and our third party vendors (except for communications necessary for the operation of the Site(s), which do not require an opt in), (2) having your contact Information disclosed to third parties (except as necessary for us to operate the Site(s), or as otherwise permitted under this Privacy Statement or required under applicable law, which, in each case, will not require an opt in). If you do not wish to receive such communications or allow such disclosures, do not opt in. You may view, correct and revise your Information by accessing your account. For example, if you have previously opted in and you would like to stop receiving communications from us and our third party vendors, or you would like to revoke any other consent previously granted for a specific purpose concerning your personally identifiable Information, then you can opt out by sending IWP an e-mail at remove@interweave.com or calling us at 800-272-2193. In the event you opt-out we may retain your email address and share your email address with our third party marketing partners, for the purpose of honoring your request to opt-out of receiving information from us or our marketing partners on our behalf. 

**Notice of Changes to the Privacy Statement  
**We may update this Privacy Statement from time to time. We will notify you about significant changes in the way we treat personally identifiable Information by sending a notice to the primary email address specified in your account or by placing a prominent notice on our Site(s). After the changes take effect, all newly collected and previously collected Information will be subject to the terms of the revised Privacy Statement. 

**Contacting Aspire Media/Interweave Press, LLC  
**If you have any questions or concerns about this Privacy Statement, you may contact us at: privacy@interweave.com
